what's up everybody this is Nick at
bobbend.com today I am talking about the
best supplement stacks on the market for
those who don't know supplement stacks
are when you buy several products as a
group to address your needs from like
various angles so a basic supplement
stack might be pre-workout protein
powder and post workout supplements
whereas a more advanced one might also
include fish oil multivitamins creatine
and so on so generally they can often be
a decent way to save money because the
company if you buy them all at once
they'll give you a discount for getting
all this stuff at the same time so they
can be a more cost effective way to meet
your needs in that regard and also just
a more comprehensive way to approach
your Fitness and your health and achieve
your goals so we've got a whole lot of
different supplement stacks we're going
to go through today we're going to be
talking about the best for weight loss
the best of my second bodybuilding the
best for vegans and more and we're also
going to answer a few commonly asked
questions so that you can make the right
decision for you now before I go any
further I should make it clear that I am
not a doctor and this is not constitute
medical advice it's an important
disclaimer for videos like this if you
are making any changes to your
supplement regimen or nutrition regimen
exercise basically any big changes in
your life make sure you speak to your
physician first so that they can make
sure it squares away with your personal
history medications you take and all
that kind of stuff so yeah touch doctor
before starting a new supplements for
now we're going to talk about the best
supplement stack for fat loss
so if you want to supplement stack
that's going to cover all your bases so
fat loss we definitely recommend huge
supplements stack for fat loss what you
got here is actually two different kinds
of fat burning products here but
together these help you get a very broad
spectrum of ingredients related to Fat
Loss you've also got a supplement here
to help with nutrient absorption and
then you've got some branched chain
amino acids which could help to preserve
muscle during fat loss potentially
anyway uh before I go any further on
that one I did want to ask the question
we always get on these sorts of
supplements which is what are the
benefits of stacking your supplements
basically a supplement stack is a
convenient and cost effective way to
group your supplements together some
ingredients in supplements in supplement
stacks as well can work synergistically
too so generally it is a cost saving
measure but also yeah some of the
ingredients can work synergistically to
help you to achieve your goals as well
so why is huge supplements stacked for
fat loss which they call shred stack
which I'm a big fan of why is this the
best one for fat loss well there are two
fat burners in it for one right now the
most important thing when you we're
trying to lose fat is a calorie deficit
of course so you can take all the
supplements in the world but if you're
still taking a thousand calories more
than you burn you're going to gain
weight instead of lose weight so keep an
eye on your calories figure that part of
the equation out first but once you've
done that ingredients like this could
potentially help in some regards so
these two fat burners here contain a
wide array of ingredients and I'm
talking about dozens of ingredients with
some interesting connections to Fat Loss
in addition to the fat burners we've
also got utilized here which is
especially meant to be useful on heavy
carbohydrate days because it contains an
array of curious ingredients that some
research suggests can help to improve
nutrient uptake and help to better
partition carbohydrates namely the idea
is that they're better at helping you to
use carbohydrates for energy as opposed
to the carbohydrates turning to Fat so
that's part of the goal here for I
utilize in addition to helping to
improve metabolic function as well last
it is branched chain amino acids here
which especially if you are not reaching
your high protein goal or if you're
going a really long time without eating
protein without eating complete proteins
or if you're fasting some have found
that taking Branch to the new asses can
potentially help with muscle retention
also when you're like exercising an
empty stomach or if you'll find it
easier to get through their workouts
when they're having some BCAAs there's a
lot of information out there about this
these videos are pretty hard because
each separate ingredient in a stack can
be you know talked about at length for a
whole 10 minutes on its own if I'm
trying to tell you every reason why
every ingredient here is useful we're
going to be here all day so I do
encourage you if you want to learn more
about how these products were selected
uh in the description below there's a
link to the article version of this
video so that'll help to answer any
questions you have
from this video
so we've got four supplements in this
huge mass stack which uh geared around
less so much about fat loss and more
about increasing and improving
indicators of muscle growth So to that
end we have a testosterone booster
you've got two anabolics and you've also
got a supplement for increasing blood
flow when you're working out right so
what are in all these supplements the
most interesting to me is enhance which
has got this nice big bolt on the front
and this has a wide range of ingredients
that are intended to help to boost
testosterone right so an obvious one
here is vitamin D vitamin D has been
shown in plenty of studies that if a
person is low on vitamin D then getting
to the recommended intake can improve
testosterone production it's also Boron
for a more temporary boost of
testosterone that some researchers
suggested there's also selenium here
which is a very hard mineral to get it's
in Brazil nuts but it's very hard to
recommended intake of it and selenium
also has some Curious links to bring
testosterone too so in addition to some
interesting plant extracts that have
been shown in more obscure studies to
have some interesting effects this also
has some micronutrients that have more
concrete links to it as well again if
you want to check out the full written
version of this article you can see the
research we're talking about in the
studies and have a close look at the
nutrition labels I just go to Google
actually if you like go to Google bar
band best supplement stacks and this
article will come right up so if that's
how you would like to digest this
information you got that option for you
[Music]
next up is the best supplement stack for
bodybuilders and for that one we're
going to one of our favorite Brands
Wolverine and their build stack so in
this one you are getting four nope you
are getting five supplements at once so
you're getting a considerable savings
there because this is a considerable
amount of supplements to buy right but
this does give you a nice handy discount
on it what you are getting here number
one creatine which is an indispensable
tool in the toolbox of anybody Builder
and almost any athlete because
bodybuilding wise which logically
focuses on Aesthetics creation helps us
bring more water into the muscles and
increase their size so there's a nice
aesthetic benefit to it but also
creatine helps with power output so it's
great for whether you are an athlete
based on like functional like strength
outputs or Aesthetics creatine can be
pretty great we've also got a beta
alanine supplement here and the
beta-alanine that's a very common
ingredient in pre-workouts because of
all pre-workout ingredients besides
caffeine that's maybe the most
compelling evidence of beta-alanine as a
means for helping with endurance so
that's in the 10 to 20 rep range if
we're talking about strength endurance
and like the one to three minute range
when it comes a cardio bodybuilders tend
to do both of those activities
especially because they tend to use
higher reps right there's also
citrulline which is an amino acid that
is non-essential found in watermelons
and citrulline also has a lot of
interesting research on it for blood
flow like vasodilation like helping with
nitric oxide production so that's going
to mean more vascularity which is a big
deal for bodybuilders but also more
blood flow more pumps and also
potentially more hypertrophy as well as
I mentioned in the previous section
there's some glutamine in here glutamine
it could potentially help to improve gut
health and it may help to build tissue
as well finally there's way I slip here
which uh doesn't mean any introduction
it's very very lean protein for
bodybuilders they're typically trying to
get as much protein density from their
protein supplements as possible so so
they sometimes avoid the cheaper way
concentrate because it has more carbs
and fat we isolate here the one from
Sovereign for a fat 26 grams of protein
you're getting half a gram of fat and
just one gram of carbohydrates so it's
basically like protein per calorie Wise
It's like a chicken breast in a bottle
but uh it tastes like cinnamon honey
peanut butter so this is a really
comprehensive stack so Wolverines build
is the best supplements stack out there
for bodybuilders
curiously It Will Rain they also have
our favorite supplement stack for vegans
and it's this except it's whey protein
here so we're just going to sort that
one out for their vegan protein and then
you have the vegan supplement stack
which we consider the best of the stack
of vegans especially with the fact that
natural forms of creatine and creatine
monohydrate the only way to get that
without a supplement is through eating
meat and there's actually been some
interesting research suggesting that
folks who don't eat a lot of meat namely
vegetarians and vegans but also the
elderly who tend to not eat much meat
much protein there have been studies
suggesting taking creatine can also help
with cognitive function as well which is
kind of cool so uh definitely creatine
is a must for folks who don't eat very
much meat also there's protein here now
that's not to say that it's impossible
to get protein on a vegan diet we were
just talking about getting a protein
supplement people not in the vegan diet
right like it doesn't matter what diet
you're on protein is typically expensive
and hard to get when you're out and
about so it's a good idea to get a
protein powder whether you're a vegan or
not right so this one here from
Sovereign this has a pretty good protein
calorie register at 22 grams of protein
3 grams of carbohydrates and two and a
half grams of fat which is a really
really solid ratio plus it's all natural
there's no artificial flavors or
sweetness or anything like that
otherwise the other ingredients here I'm
not going to boil because I just said
them all in the previous section but all
of these are good for ergogenic
performance and hypertrophy so if you
are a vegan learn to gain muscle or even
just perform better in the gym then this
is a great supplement stack these
Wolverine vegan supplement stack
[Music]
next up is our favorite supplement stack
for beginners and that one is from
transparent labs they call this the
muscle building Essentials stack so what
you're getting in the transparent lab
stack it's just like a nice basic
comprehensive approach that isn't like
really really Advanced like bizarre
ingredients never heard of except for
lumberzone never heard of which is in
their growth pill this is called
phosphatidic acid and there's been some
interesting research suggesting they're
taking this in conjunction with a
resistance training plan when compared
to the placebo they found more than one
study on this that are found to when
everything else was equal it increased
muscle mass to a greater degree than
those not taking phosphatic acid and
also there's a study that found there
was more power production more strength
in the lower body which also can lead to
more high five screen more muscle growth
as well right next up is creatine ATM B
we've already talked all about the
benefits of creatine monohydrate what
transparent Labs has done here is that
they've combined it with a metabolite of
the amino acid leucine called hydroxy
methyl butyrate and there's a little bit
of interesting research who suggests
that when creating an hmb are coming
bind it helps to retain muscle a little
better than either of them alone so it's
an anti-catabolic agent potentially
anyway interesting research there we've
also of course got some away protein
powder here this is grass-fed whey
protein isolate so as mentioned before
isolates they tend to be very low in
carbohydrates and fat relative to whey
concentrate and this actually has 28
grams of protein for one gram of
carbohydrates and zero grams of fat so
it's just a very shockingly protein
dense again that's that's more protein
dense than chicken breast so that's
that's really nice touch lastly there is
their pre-workout called bulk and bulk
is a pre-workout that is designed to uh
you know give you a great workout but
also some extra ingredients that could
potentially help to further facilitate
muscle building so by that I mean it has
a lot of ingredients that have links in
research to improve power output like
the beta in anhydrous are improved
endurance like beta-alanine which you
mentioned earlier all of these sorts of
ingredients if you're getting a better
workout because you're taking these
ingredients that makes them effective
muscle building agents like because most
of it comes down to how much work are
you doing in the gym before I can help
you do that then that's like really a
big key to muscle building right so in
addition to all those pre-workout
ingredients which again are actually
very effective for helping you build
muscle if it's letting you work out
longer and better there's also got some
Boron here which has some links with
testosterone production as well as a
good amount of zinc too which again if
you're low in zinc that could impact
testosterone production as well so the
best supplement stack for beginners in
our opinion is the one from transparent
Labs the muscle building Essentials
stack
[Music]
so next up we're going to move away from
the gym now and to your bathroom we're
going to talk about the best supplement
stack for Digestive Health that also
comes from Sovereign
so I'm going to work up to the cool ones
here right I'm going to start off with
glutamine glutamine is actually the
preferred fuel source for the gut this
is in the stack by the way this is also
in this stack so glutamine is the
preferred fuel source for the gut it
uses up a lot of it and there's uh
evidence is suggested yeah glutamine
supplementation like among folks with
IBS there's been some positive results
seen and it appears that glutamine helps
the gut to prevent bad bacteria like you
know malignant bacteria from entering
the small intestine or the bowel wall so
that seems to be kind of cool stuff with
glutamine in addition to that we've got
turmeric uh there's a turmeric
supplement here with a lot of curcumin
in it now you might have heard of
curcumin before it is a very powerful
anti-inflammatory agent I believe it's
also found in ginger but the reason why
turmeric is always considered a
superfood is because of this
anti-inflammatory agent called curcumin
in it so in addition to being a very
strong anti-inflammatory aging like a
lot of people take it for inflammatory
issues like arthritis this is not
medical information talk to your doctor
before taking in immune supplements
there's also some data to suggest that
the way that curcumin has an
anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effect
on the gut may help to modulate gut
bacteria and gut bacteria are important
for digestion breaking down nutrients
but also there's evidence to suggest
that having a healthy population of gut
bacteria can not only help to minimize
suggested distress in an array of
conditions not all of them but some of
them but also it could help with
immunity mental health a whole bunch of
stuff like that so that's pretty cool
lastly we have regular old probiotics
which if you are into Digestive Health
that might be the only thing you've
actually heard of on this list as a
means for helping digestive health so
what's cool as they've got some
interesting new ingredients like the
glutamine and the turmeric that has some
promising research behind it but also
some more established supplements that
have been around for a bit longer for
this purpose like probiotics you're
getting 5.75 billion probiotic bacteria
per serving with this one and what's
extra cool about that is that they come
from seven different families of
bacteria because not just the probiotic
bacteria that is good to have it's not
just good to have a lot of them it's
good to have a diverse population of
them from an array of sources so yeah
the digestive health stack from
Sovereign has a wide array of
ingredients that can help to improve gut
health potentially from an array of
different angles from like helping with
gut permeability potentially to uh
helping with probiotic count to the
probiotica diversity and so on so
our favorite supplement stack four
digestive health is soberings
lastly we've got the best supplement
stack for women and it is from the
female Focus supplement brand ideal fit
they've got kind of a sub brand called
ideal lean and that's where they focus
on supplements for women this is an
ideal supplement stack for women who are
looking to improve their Fitness in
particular so what we've got here is
three products number one is I've got a
protein powder they've also got a
pre-workout and there is a branched
chain amino acid now if you've been
watching this video so far there's a
good time you've already heard me talk
all about the benefits of various
pre-workout ingredients this contains
plenty of the Soul what's you already
know about like beta in anhydrous for
power beta alumine for endurance and so
on all these Classics the ingredients
aren't really different from the other
pre-workouts we've mentioned so far
Branch amino acids if you recall those
are three types of amino acids with
close links to muscle protein synthesis
long story short if you're in a calorie
deficit and you're not eating like a lot
of protein throughout the day and also
if you're having a long gap between
meals or maybe if you're fasting or if
you're exercising on an empty stomach
plenty of people have found the
branching amino acids there's some
research suggesting it can help to
improve muscle retention namely make
sure that what you're losing is losing
fat then this protein powder is protein
we've covered that already now you might
be wondering we've talked a bit about
pre-workouts and BCAAs and protein
powders so far in this video what makes
these for women number one this
pre-workout is actually stimulant free
meaning it's like free from caffeine
there are a lot of pre-workouts out
there that are really overloaded on
caffeine this just has those ingredients
I mentioned earlier like beta-alanine
and beta in these sorts of things with
interesting benefits for performance but
without making you really wired because
those aren't actual stimulants at all
they're just going to potentially
improve your workout but you'll still be
able to sleep so a lot of people prefer
non-stem pre-workout for that reason the
other reason these are designed for
women is that they have better flavors
that's like the main difference between
like supplements for the Board of Public
and the supplements for in Brands like
this is you get more delicious flavors
and I'm really jealous and I have a
course but many many products from ideal
lean myself despite not being a woman so
like the protein powders they've got
like Fruity cereal you got white
chocolate you've got cold brew coffee I
haven't seen any other companies put out
flavors like this they're really great
the BCAAs uh I've got a I've had
blueberry pomegranate from them before
there's peach rings there's pink
lemonade basically yeah women get better
selections of more delicious flavors and
uh I'm very jealous and so I'm always
buying them myself best up on stack for
women is from ideal leans supplement
stuff
foreign
[Music]
really exhausting video on the best
supplement stacks on the market uh
before you go and buy a supplement stack
like just things to keep in mind with
this sort of endeavor is you want to
have a good think about what you want to
achieve from these products so like for
instance whether you are trying to like
let's say lose fat we have two fat
burners here there is interesting
research supporting them like maybe
helping to oxidize more fat than you
would have otherwise but by far the most
important component of losing fat is to
be in a calorie deficit so you know make
sure that you are in a calorie deficit
make sure you do that homework to find
out how many calories you tend to eat if
Atlas is the goal of yours you also need
to have like a good protein intake
there's a lot more to it than just
taking a fat burner same goes the muscle
gain supplements but in Reverse like are
there products here that contain some
ingredients that could help with blood
flow that might help you to gain like
slightly more muscle than you would have
otherwise yeah potentially but that's
gonna be a very very small difference
and it's like really going to make much
of a difference at all if you aren't
making sure that you're in a slight
calorie excess and you're getting plenty
of protein and carbohydrate if your
issues I did with digestion you know
like these products here could help but
you also want to make sure that you are
getting plenty of fiber and plenty of
fruits and vegetables to fill in any
gaps in your diet and also that you're
speaking to your doctor so the point I'm
trying to make here is that these are
supplements they're not the backbone of
your entire diet or your entire life
even though you're getting something in
Stacks which can potentially be better
than just getting single supplements at
like rounding out your supplement
routine and making a kind of a holistic
approach to whatever goal you're trying
to accomplish here so that's what I'm
trying to convey here supplement stacks
can be a more effective way to achieve
your goals than getting a single
supplement alone but make sure they are
just part of the overall puzzle and if
they can be deducted to make sure you're
covering all your bases elsewhere that's
our video thank you very much for
watching if you want to see a written
version of this video so you can go
through this at your own pace and
without my accent you can Google bar
band best supplement stacks and it'll
come right up and that'll give you
everything you want to know for now
it's time for me to go thanks for
watching again and we'll catch you for
the next video
[Music]